<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Raging Scholars</title><link href="www.hailang.me/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://feed.hailang.me/feeds/Misc!.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>www.hailang.me/</id><updated>2013-09-08T00:00:00+08:00</updated><entry><title>How to Differentiate China Chinese &amp; Local Chinese for Dummies</title><link href="www.hailang.me/posts/2013/Sep/differentiate-china-chinese-and-local-chinese/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-09-08T00:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Hai Lang</name></author><id>tag:www.hailang.me,2013-09-08:posts/2013/Sep/differentiate-china-chinese-and-local-chinese/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="preface"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Preface&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often times people ask me whether or not a guy/girl comes from China. I was
quite annoyed by such questions back then since I thought it's obvious to tell
the difference between what I call &lt;em&gt;'China Chinese'&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;'Local Chinese'&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realized that I was wrong when I failed to differentiate &lt;em&gt;'India Indians'&lt;/em&gt; and
&lt;em&gt;'Local Indians'&lt;/em&gt;, and my friend Kumar can judge even by the way how they
walk. I started to get the hang of it after he explained me some tricks, and
then I thought, hey, maybe I can do everyone a favor and share some basic tips
on how to do the same trick on my beloved Chinese fellows ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="about-this-guide"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;About This Guide&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are about to go after some Chinese guy/girl or just want to expand your
social circle to have more Chinese friends, and you are troubled by the
difference between &lt;em&gt;'China Chinese'&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;'Local Chinese&lt;/em&gt;', but you have none or
minimal knowledge of any kind of Chinese culture, and you don't speak Mandarin,
Cantonese, or Hokkien, then no worries, this guide is for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="technical-stuff-you-can-skip-this-safely"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Technical Stuff (You can skip this safely)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For starters, most local Chinese originated from southern part of China,
namely Guangdong and Fujian province. The dialects they speak are Cantonese and
Hokkien accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Map of China" class="align-center" src="www.hailang.me/static/images/china_map.gif" style="width: 640.0px; height: 420.0px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As shown in the map above, including Hainan island, the last three rows on the map
are normally considered as the &lt;em&gt;'Southern China'&lt;/em&gt;. All Chinese folks share the same
written language, but the difference between dialects, esp. southern vs northern are
often overwhelming even to a native Chinese speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We share roughly the same culture, with slight differences between provinces. Knowing
some of the differences can even help to tell which province a person comes from. It
becomes rather obvious when it comes to southern vs. northern.
For instance, people are still arguing whether &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zongzi"&gt;Zongzi&lt;/a&gt; should be salty or sweetened
throughout different parts of China. (I'm team sweet by the way.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As what I said, most &lt;em&gt;'Local Chinese'&lt;/em&gt;'s forefathers were born and rised in Guangdong,
Fujian, and in some cases Hainan, hijacked by our beloved British, and travelled all
the way to Malaysia / Indonesia / America and so on. Although generations of living in
another country has developped them some strange (no offence) habbits, they still carry
some rather distinct and obvious culture heritages from their home provinces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, most &lt;em&gt;'China Chinese'&lt;/em&gt; you meet nowadays are highly unlikely from
Guangdong or Fujian (Look at the sizes of all other provinces and imagine the population
there). And even if they do come from the said provinces, Mandarin is now the official
language we speak throughout China, and that greatly affects our English accents (I'll
talk about it later).
And this is the foundation of our theory, knowing the differences between these
two provinces and all others would be sufficient to master the art of differentiating
Chinese folks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="here-comes-the-actual-guide"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Here Comes the Actual Guide&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCLAIMER&lt;/strong&gt;: This guide is just for fun. Appologize if I offended anyone in anyway&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A. The way we speak English&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="loweralpha simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a person speaks English with a trailing &lt;em&gt;'Lah'&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;'Mah'&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;'Loh'&lt;/em&gt; etc.
He/She is a Local.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a person speaks English with the Russel Peter's classic Chinese accent.
He/She is a Local.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a person speaks English like 'chopping vegetables' and trying so hard on every
pronunciation. He/She comes from China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;China Chinese pronunce &lt;em&gt;'head'&lt;/em&gt; as &lt;em&gt;'hand'&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;'world'&lt;/em&gt; as &lt;em&gt;'word'&lt;/em&gt;, etc. Anything
involving tongue-twisting is mission impossible to us.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;img alt="Ambulance" class="align-center" src="www.hailang.me/static/images/ambulance.jpg" style="width: 240.0px; height: 320.0px;" /&gt;
&lt;ol class="loweralpha simple" start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local Chinese generally speaks better English.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But ironically, people from China pay more attention to grammars even we sometimes
can't handle the pronunciation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B. The way we dress&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="loweralpha simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a person wears sunglasses. He/She is probably from China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;img alt="Chinese love sunglasses" class="align-center" src="www.hailang.me/static/images/sunglasses.jpg" style="width: 510.0px; height: 320.0px;" /&gt;
&lt;ol class="loweralpha simple" start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a person wears shorts/slippers. He/She is probably a Local.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Similarly (esp for guys) if you've never seen a person wearing shorts/slippers.
He/She is from China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a person dresses with an overwhelmed sense of 'fashion'.
He/She is from China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Similarly, if a person has no sense of fashion whatsoever.
He/She is a Local.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you see a guy with a huge water bottle all the time.
He/She is definitely a Local.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C. How our names look like&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="loweralpha simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a you can't comfortablly pronunce a person's name.
He/She is from China.
(My name is pronunced as High Long, and yes I freaking love it)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you can easily pronunce a person's name, but it made you laugh.
He/She is Local.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We China Chinese don't usually have christian names. Except for when we call Dominos.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;img alt="Christian Names" class="align-center" src="www.hailang.me/static/images/christian_names.jpg" style="width: 510.0px; height: 320.0px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D. The way we drive&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="loweralpha simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a person horns a lot while driving.
He/She is from China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a person curses a lot while driving.
He/She is from China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a person drives in a great haste as if someone's going to deliver a baby.
He/She is from China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you find a Chinese guy in a car accident scene.
He/She is Local (just kidding.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;img alt="Drive In" class="align-center" src="www.hailang.me/static/images/drive-in.jpg" style="width: 510.0px; height: 320.0px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;E. The way we drink/party/clubbing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="loweralpha simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you've never seen a person drunk.
He/She is from China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a person leaves in the middle to 'send gf/bf home'.
He/She is from China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a person shouts like a Russian after getting drunk.
He/She is from China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a person drinks a lot but never dance.
He/She is from China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a person dances a lot but can't drink.
He/She is Local.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a person drinks in a way as if he/she's trying to close a deal with you.
He/She is from China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;img alt="Cheers" class="align-center" src="www.hailang.me/static/images/cheers.jpg" style="width: 510.0px; height: 320.0px;" /&gt;
&lt;ol class="loweralpha simple" start="7"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a girl orders bloody mary. She's from China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a guy orders bloody mary. He's a Local. (Sorry...)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;F. The way we text&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="loweralpha simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a person uses &lt;em&gt;'XD'&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;'LMAO'&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;'OMFG'&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;'IDK'&lt;/em&gt; a lot.
He/She is a Local.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a person uses &lt;em&gt;'^_^'&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;'^ω^'&lt;/em&gt;', &lt;em&gt;'T_T'&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;'-_-'&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;'LOL'&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;'hehe'&lt;/em&gt;,  a lot.
He/She is from China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;img alt="Chinese Text Style" class="align-center" src="www.hailang.me/static/images/chinese_text.jpg" style="width: 510.0px; height: 320.0px;" /&gt;
&lt;ol class="loweralpha simple" start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a person always put &lt;em&gt;'~'&lt;/em&gt; at the end of each sentence.
He/She is from China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a person uses extensive amount of &lt;em&gt;'.....'&lt;/em&gt;. He/She is from China&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;G. The way we curse/fight&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="loweralpha simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a person curses in a funny way.
He/She is a Local.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a person never curse. He/She is from China.
(Our English proficiency doesn't allow us to curse effectively.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a person threats to call his/her gang. He/She is from China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;img alt="Cheers" class="align-center" src="www.hailang.me/static/images/chinese_gang.jpg" style="width: 510.0px; height: 320.0px;" /&gt;
&lt;ol class="loweralpha simple" start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a person fights in a boxing style. He/She is a Local.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H. The way we eat&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="loweralpha simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People obsessed with Pizza/McD/KFC are most likely from China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People obsessed with instant noodles are most likely from China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People obsessed with spicy food are most likely from China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If someone knows how to actually make dumplings, He/She's from China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If someone looks angry having so-called 'Chinese food', He/She's from China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If someone looks grumpy having Chinese food, He/She's a Local.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A person who asks for chopstick when having Pizzahut / Thai Food is a Local.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A person who insists on using dining knife and forks comes from China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I. The way we shop&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="loweralpha simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a person (esp. girls) is obsessed with luxury brands.
He/She is from China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a preson knows many brands but failed to pronunce their names.
He/She is from China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a person looks like He/She owns the place, and is about to fire everyone while walking
into a luxury brand outlet. He/She is from China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you see someone buying large amount of bags or cosmetics. He/She is from China,
buying gifts for relatives and friends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conclusion"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll just stop here. This is no way near a &lt;em&gt;Definitive Guide&lt;/em&gt;, I just listed some of the
obvious/funny/interesting differences. And you are welcome to add more to the comment section below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Appologize to all my Chinese fellows and friends, no offence intended. I love you all! ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;EOF&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>马来西亚的幸福留学生活</title><link href="www.hailang.me/posts/2013/Jul/my-happy-life-in-malaysia/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-07-15T00:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Hai Lang</name></author><id>tag:www.hailang.me,2013-07-15:posts/2013/Jul/my-happy-life-in-malaysia/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;从2008年5月第一次来马来西亚算起，这已经是我在这里的第五年了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我曾经一度对马来西亚充满了归属感，短期回国的休假总让我像思念故乡一样思念马来西亚。每次从
亚航舱门简陋的铁梯走下来的时候一定要深吸几口那温暖潮湿的空气，充满了自由的味道，无拘无束
又蕴含着恰到好处的闲适。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我也曾一直认为马来西亚本应该是个闲适的地方，一切都不紧不慢，不急不徐。慢慢地习惯了一个星
期只有两天课还放假放到蛋疼的忧伤，也慢慢习惯了点菜后等半个小时还不见踪影的无奈，这些在这
个奇怪的地方都仿佛顺理成章，毋容质疑似的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;每个人对这里都有不同的评价：有些人说绿化好，有些人说多民族文化好，有人说地方小憋屈，有人
说治安差，有人说海边美...我却对这里有一种特殊的亲近感。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这里是我的地盘。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我曾背着苹果顶配的笔记本，揣着时兴的苹果手机，家里还摆着21寸苹果一体机，连车屁股上也贴着
苹果的标志，从头到脚把自己包裹在小资的光环里。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我曾门门拿A，动辄满分，平常没心没肺期末随手一挥摇身一变成优等生，闷声发财，惊煞外国友人。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我也曾风光无限，满分录取学校研发部，设计组组长，项目经理，核心开发，全校大半的新服务器都
在我手上，没事挂着员工胸卡四处晃悠，上台演个讲俨然是教授风范。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我一度恬不知耻地认为这些都是我应得的，我成绩优异，上司期许，老师青睐，学校里人人尊重，随
便去打听一下有几个中国留学生不知道我的名字的？做人嘛，腰杆要挺得直，我车自己供，房租自己
交，大三学费也自己从工资里扣，对得起良心父母，有谁敢说句闲话？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;俗话说人狂就他妈被狗咬，这样的光环我也没戴得了多长。从加拿大没去成开始，被拖走了新车，典
当了电脑，变卖了手机，才发现自己赤条条冷清清，屁都不是。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;滚回研究所再上班，看到的却是另一番光景。我已经隐约是个大龄青年了，为了给我曾经的所谓辉煌
买单，三年的课程拖到了五年；为了一个月在低保线上挣扎的工资，熬夜加班变卖廉价劳动力；为了
混学生签证，名不正言不顺得还是个没编制的实习生。曾经作为学生看似光环的所谓成就，现在有如
鸡肋 -- 食之无味，弃之可惜。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;还逞什么英雄好汉？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;前段时间的我像一只斗败的公鸡，唯唯诺诺庸庸碌碌，每天在计算的就是什么时候发工资，剩下的钱
还够不够吃饭。不由得让我想起了那个27岁“才”博士毕业的Andrew Wiles，被人认为是智商有问题。
咱搞电脑的不比自然科学，但那最少也得24岁硕士毕业，后面再混个博士随便找个野鸡大学当个终身
教授才有点大师范啊。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;看来我智商有问题，半瓶子不满还乱晃悠，你看看，仅有的那么点水平都晃光了吧？活该。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我最近发现人生是个很贱的东西，你越看不上生活的恩赐和照顾，你得到的越多，反而你越垂死挣扎
夜不能寐地追求，却往往竹篮打水。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我还发现我的另一个巨大的潜力，逆来顺受，破罐破摔倒常常是我的拿手好戏。怨不得天地政府，
你还能怎样呢？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;最开心的是周五，楼下熙熙攘攘的人群，天刚一黑就能闻到各种夜市小吃的味道。每个星期五也是我
开荤的时候，那家马来人的羊排我是必买的。拿着夹子挑一块最肥的，还要注意挑没骨头的，不然花
十几块买大半块骨头那可是要一整个星期愉快不起来的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;当然还要有鸡饭哥的平民鸡饭。三块五还能加米饭，我一度怀疑他是专门来做慈善的。羊排要多来一
勺肉汁，回家一口气全浇进鸡饭里拌开了吃。吃完就缓缓的躺下，摸着肚子感慨人生也就不过如此了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;呵呵。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;眼看着学生签证马上要到期了，最搞笑的是我们学校，自己的学生竟然不发毕业证就不给办工作签，
其他公司可没听说过这么个无厘头的规定。可恶英国鬼下次来审查毕业成绩就得年底了，我要想留下
还得自备学生签证。大选刚完的马来西亚，执政党花的钱总得想尽办法揩回来，190块的签证费也一跃
变成了一千多，为了继续给他们剥削我还得自己买单吃半个月泡面，不知道是学校贱还是我自己贱。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;朋友推荐了个工作，面试了两次就发来了合同。一个月4000做项目经理，看得我心花怒放啊。哥终于
要有存款了吗？终于月底不用数硬币吃饭了吗？终于可以换手机了吗？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;形格势禁，到底是个小公司，管理混乱鱼龙混杂，剩下个烂摊子让我接手。最要命的是他们做游戏开
发的，你感觉我长得像爱玩游戏的人吗？“宁缺毋滥”，海老板说，有道理，不去。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;最近看上Quintiq这个公司，在马来西亚搞了个全球开发中心，专门做供应链优化什么的。财大气粗
当然架子也要大，想面试就得先解一道日程问题。然后数学测试，最后技术测试。你都过了人家还不
一定要你，什么时候缺人了从全过的人里挑几个而已。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Challenge Accepted. 哥就喜欢有挑战的东西。那几周没日没夜地算题，基因算法，模拟退火，SAT
全整上了，做梦都在解题。正巧研究所要做部署，连续加班了1个月，周末都没休息过。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;也许是积劳成疾吧，上周早上起来开始吐血，吐了半天也吐不完，心里也怯了，看来人不得志大都会
早衰吧。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;然后又各种恶补数学，通宵看书。题也解出来了，数学测试也过了，打电话一问人家10月份才要人，
你老母的知道不知道哥签证九月就过期了？知不知道哥为了解你那破题花了多少心思？我欲待你如初
恋，你却虐我千百遍，很爽吗？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;接着茫然。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我到底在追求什么？更好的工作，更好的生活，更高的工资？我到底要用我的人生实现什么？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;天资同学说目前留在国外就好，和学校签约了。Wiles寒窗十年也从一个“智商有问题”的低能儿变成
证明了费马大定理的风云人物。人最怕的是没目标，但我现在已经不敢有目标了。若结局总是破灭，
当初何必希冀？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;最近开始吃1200mg的Piracetam了，本来那两天熬夜看书的时候为了缓解头疼的，现在权当抗抑郁
药吧。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;闭上眼睛，扑腾着我想象的翅膀极目远眺。我看到有个我穿着长衫，站着吃酒，面红耳赤地和店小二
争执茴香豆的茴字到底是有四种写法，还是五种写法；另一个我正站在街旁，手中拿着一副夹子，来
来回回地挑一块肥羊肉。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt; EOF&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="misc"></category></entry><entry><title>New Blog</title><link href="www.hailang.me/posts/2013/Apr/new-blog/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-04-11T00:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Hai Lang</name></author><id>tag:www.hailang.me,2013-04-11:posts/2013/Apr/new-blog/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've been looking for a better blogging platform for quite a while. &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://cloudhead.io/toto"&gt;Toto&lt;/a&gt; is a great project but there are just
too many things to customize, and I really miss tagging and categories ;-p&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I changed to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://blog.getpelican.com/"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt;. It's customizable, fast, it generates static HTML pages. And yea, it supports tags and
categories (YEEEEA!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually lost some of my posts when I was migrating my old wordpress blog to Toto, so in order to prevent
this from happening again. I'm just gonna create a new subdomain for the Toto site, and slowly migrate those
posts to this new site (yea I'm a lazy ass).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just in case if anyone wants to see my older posts (The FreeBSD Rootkit Design series)
while I'm migrating, just use &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://old.hailang.me"&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;EOF&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term=""></category></entry></feed>